best-poems.net 2019-11-03

# PRIVACY POLICY | Best Poems

**1\. Overview**  
We, at The Best Poems Encyclopedia (the “Encyclopedia”), recognize that privacy of your personal information is important and are committed to protecting the privacy and security needs of those who visit our website and who publish texts in our website. This Privacy Policy describes what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit best-poems.net (as defined in the Terms), and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. 

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post any changes to this Privacy Policy here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose that information to anyone. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis. By using our Website, or any of the texts or resources that we provide on this site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**2\. Collection and Use of Information**

**WHAT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU IS COLLECTED ON OUR WEBSITE?**  
We collect personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you (“Personally Identifiable Information”). Such Personally Identifiable Information may include your name and email address.  
You do not have to provide us with any Personally Identifiable Information to visit our Website. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, you may not be able to publish texts online. 

**WHERE AND WHEN INFORMATION IS COLLECTED ON OUR WEBSITE**  
We may collect Personally Identifiable Information from you in different manners and at different places on our Website, such as when you register to the Best Poems Newsletter, or create New Account in our Website. In all of these cases, we will collect Personally Identifiable Information from you only if you voluntarily submit such information to us. 

**LOG FILES**  
As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

**COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS**  
We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. We also use third party advertisements on best-poems.net to support our educational non-profit website. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York poetry publishers ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing forums ads to someone who frequents forums sites).

**DOUBLECLICK DART COOKIES**  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about How to Publish you poems, you may see Poetry Publishers advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about music). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting https://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into your account.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

**USE OF INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT**  
In general, we use the information collected on our Website to help us understand who uses our Website, to improve our Website. On occasion, we may send you information on new offerings regarding poetry publishing opportunities or upcoming events. However, if you do not wish to receive E-mailed marketing messages from us, please let us know by sending an E-mail to staff@best-poems.net or writing us using the contact form in our Contact Page. 

**WHEN WE DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**  
Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose any information we gather from you on our Website.  
We may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if we believe in good faith that we are required by law to do so. We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information in special circumstances when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to protect the safety and/or security of our users, our Website, or the general public.

**DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY WHEN I LINK TO OTHER WEBSITES?**  
Our Website contains links to other websites not owned or operated by the Best Poems Encyclopedia. We are not responsible for the content, accuracy, privacy practices and performance of those websites. We encourage you to be aware when our Website links to other websites and read the privacy policies or statements of each and every website. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected by our Website. 

**IS THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT SECURE?**  
We want your information, including your Personally Identifiable Information, to remain as secure as possible. We strive to secure transmission of your information from your computer to the server where our website is hosted through industry-standard techniques. Only our editors and hosting employees who need access to our scripts files to perform a specific task or function are granted access to such information. 

**3\. General Information**

**UPDATING AND CORRECTING MY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION.**  
You can always contact us in order to (1) update or correct your Personally Identifiable Information, (2) change your preferences with respect to communications and other information you may receive from us, or (3) delete the Personally Identifiable Information maintained about you on our systems, by contacting our webmaster at the address set out below. Such updates, corrections, changes and deletions will not have an effect on other information that we maintain, or information that we have provided to third-parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy prior to such update, correction, change or deletion. 

You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us on our systems. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your Personally Identifiable Information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. We promise that promptly after receiving your request, all Personally Identifiable Information stored in databases we actively use and other readily searchable media will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted as appropriate, as soon as reasonably practicable. 

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY.**  
If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our Website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use Personally Identifiable Information in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you, at the time it was collected, we will notify you by posting changes on our Website in this Privacy Policy, or by email or otherwise, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your Personally Identifiable Information in the new manner. We may also make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that generally will not affect our use of your Personally Identifiable Information. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should not use our Website. 

**CONTACT REGARDING PRIVACY QUESTIONS**  
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or feel that we are not abiding by the terms of our posted Privacy Policy, please contact our editorial staff in any of the following ways:  

E-mail our Staff  
staff@best-poems.net 

**BY USING OUR WEBSITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE OUR WEBSITE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF OUR WEBSITE FOLLOWING THE POSTING OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY WILL MEAN THAT YOU ACCEPT THOSE CHANGES.**
